J +54 9 291 422-1556

☑ federico.fapitalle@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/federico-fapitalle/

• https://github.com/ffapitalle

Summary of qualifications

Senior System Administrator with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor degree in Computer Science from Universidad Nacional del Sur.

Currently interested in automation and continuous integration. Capable of working in teams, in a collaborative fashion as well as independently, in an autonomous way.

Interested in ongoing professional development, mentoring other team members and research.

Work experience

Feb 2021 - Present

Containers & DevOps Content Developer *Red Hat* Designs and develops technical training curriculum and labs for customer base using deep technical expertise. Ensures that training courses address all levels of customers in the use of company products/services. Leads crossfunctional efforts with engineering to develop specifications for course content. Assesses customer needs for future course development. Uses technical expertise to resolve escalated customer tickets and write reference architectures for newly discovered bugs.

Jul 2018 - Jan 2021

DevOps Engineer *Avature* Designs, develops and deploys configuration management infrastructure. Implements continuous deployment and continuous integrations pipelines. Mentors development teams to define their infrastructure needs.

Dec 2014 - Jun 2018

Senior System Engineer *Avature* Plans, develops and maintains on-premise and cloud-based servers that compose the company infrastructure. Ensures high availability of critical services and monitors real time behaviour. Performs mainteinance and performance tuning tasks over SLA time frames.

Jan 2009 - Nov 2014

System / **Network Administrator** *Cooperativa Obrera Ltda.* Plans, develops and maintains onpremise servers that compose the company infrastructure. Ensures high availability of critical services and monitors real time behaviour.

Dec 2002 - Dec 2008

Software Developer *Cooperativa Obrera Ltda.* Designs, develops, tests and deploys a PoS system, based on Linux, C++ and a PoS backend dashboard, based on PHP and Mysql. Installs, maintains,

and configures Linux servers for running all PoS components.

Sep 2002 - Nov 2002

Technical Support Enginner *Garcia Navarro & Cia. S.A.* Performs first level technical support. Executes help desk tasks. Assists employees with computer related issues. Plans and deploys a small size LAN network for an annex office.

Jan 2002 - May 2002

Network Architect Intern *Schlumberger* Works closely to the Network Architect, researches on application response times of a global application.

Feb 2001 - Dec 2001

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant *Universidad Nacional del Sur* Mentors students to understand the course contents. Helps the instructor to teach. Conducts the exams.

Education

Universidad Nacional del Sur Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

"Licenciado en Ciencias de la Computacion"

1996 - 2001.

Universidad Nacional de La Plata Master's degree, Computer Science

"Magister en Redes de Datos"

2013 - Unfinished

Certifications

Learning Docker Nov 2020. *Linkedin Learning*.

Getting Started with Google Kubernetes Engine Sep 2020. Coursera. See credential Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) Jun 2013. Red Hat. See credential

Publications

- Fapitalle, F., Echaiz, J., Ardenghi, J. (2005) Control de Tráfico y Administración de Ancho de Banda en Linux con tcng. VII Workshop de Investigadores en Ciencias de la Computación (WICC 2005), ISBN 950-665-337-2, pp. 203-207. Universidad Nacional de Río Cuarto, Córdoba, May 13th-14th. http://es.scribd.com/doc/37291617/44-TRAFICO
- Fapitalle, F., Vazquez, G.E., Ponzoni, I., & Brignole, N.B. (2002) A Descentralized Parallel-Distributed Observability Algorithm. *Fifth World Congress on Computational Mechanics (WCCM V), July 7th-12th, Viena, Austria.* Editors: Mang, H.A.; Rammerstorfer, F.G.; Eberhardsteiner, J., Publisher: Vienna University of Technology, Austria, ISBN 3-9501554-0-6.
- Fapitalle, F., Vazquez, G.E., Ponzoni, I., & Brignole, N.B. (2001) Algoritmos Paralelos/Distribuidos para Búsquedas en Profundidad sobre Grafos. *Mecánica Computacional, Vol. XX*, pp. 468-473, *AMCA*. http://www.amcaonline.org.ar/ojs/index.php/mc/article/view/1825